Welcome to the last topic of AP US
History in under 3 minutes. My intro
here will just be to simply say thank
you to you all for a wonderful year
together and let's get into it. So not
to be abrupt here, but 9/11. It is an
event we all know. Planes will crash
into the World Trade Center and the
Pentagon in a coordinated terrorist
attack carried out by the group
Al-Qaeda. This is shocking to the US at
the time and it is a very unprecedented
event. And so the US response to this
will be to enact a war on terror. And if
you were like me and wonder how exactly
you can enact a war on an ideology,
well, really what the war on terror was
was a war in Afghanistan targeting the
terrorist group responsible for 9/11,
Al-Qaeda, and the Taliban government
that supported the group. And also the
war on terror expanded to Iraq for
reasons originally justified by claims
of weapons of mass destruction. It's
also important to note that the US
depended a lot on oil coming from the
Middle East and so a lot of
complications arose over energy because
of the military actions happening in
that region. So the US shifts. They
don't have Cold War enemies anymore.
Their big enemy now is instead a terror.
And this will even expand to the home
front with a Patriot Act where the US
expanded a law enforcement surveillance
powers and strengthened measures against
terrorism financing. If you were a
supporter of this act, you might note
the need to keep Americans safe, but
critics of this act might say this
violates civil liberties and privacy
[music] rights. But anyway, for one last
time, let's look at the US. What can we
say at the end of this course? [music]
Well, the US is the most powerful nation
in the world. That is pretty objective.
The US will continue to intervene
internationally, influence global
politics, and lead economically and
militarily. My goodness, the curriculum
here really makes me glaze the heck out
of the US. Whatever, I suppose. For the
last time, on the screen now are AP
style questions for this topic. And as
you answer these questions, just know
that I have had a lot of fun over the
past few years making these history
videos. Oh, and here are your answers.
Please do tune in to the end of the year
live streams if [music] you'd like.
That's all for me though. It has been an
honor. Bye-bye.